### **Conor Desmond**

4 Stafford Street, Loudonville, NY, 12211 P: 518-469-0921 | Email: conordesmond28@yahoo.com

Accomplished programming professional, who specialized in sports-related predictive analytics with DataRobot. Recognized for team building and team motivation. Able to manage multiple tasks, meet tight deadlines and predict complex outcomes. A driven, self-starter who is adept at relationship building, programming, and providing results.

Key strengths:

Operations

Analytics

Perseverance

Data Modeling

Scouting

Management

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### REGENERON PHARMACEUTICALS - East Greenbush, NY

May 2023 - August 2023

#### Intern, Process Sciences

- Using Excel, added to a template for a unified data hierarchy from the current data hierarchy configurations
- Also, I designed graphs based on the template, led focus groups, designed a poster for my project; presented on my project in front of my department

# SOCIAL MEDIA POSTS X predictions

2022 - 2023

Before the playoffs began, using my predictive data models built in DataRobot, I predicted the 2022 MLB World Series winner, 2023 NBA finals winner, 2023 Super Bowl teams, Georgia to make the 2023 CFP championship, and my predicted RA/GM in the 2022 MLB playoffs for the Astros and Phillies were only off only .06 runs. Check the pinned tweet from my X account: @conord282 and my Github: ConorD28

### **CERTIFICATES**

## Sports Management Worldwide; Portland, Oregon, USA Baseball Analytics, Scoutables Certificate, 2023

Training included: sabermetrics, role of analytics in MLB, advanced baseball statistics, data-driven advanced scouting, and in-game preparation, how to capture & analyze baseball data.

(Mentored by Scoutables Founder, Ari Kaplan)

Reference: Dr. Lynn Lashbrook, President, Sports Management Worldwide, 503-445-7105 Ari Kaplan, kaplanball@gmail.com

Rapsodo Pitching Certificate, Jun 2023

Skills: R, SQL, Java, Python, some C++, SPSS Modeler, Excel, Problem-solving; some Spanish

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science – Marist College – 2024; GPA – 3.7 Concentration: Data Science and Analytics, Mathematics (Minor) Spanish Biliteracy Seal – Shaker High School – 2020

### **AWARDS / AFFILIATIONS**

Analyst, Baseball Committee part of Marist's Sports Analytics Club - 2022 and 2023
DataFest Participant, Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, NY - 2022 and 2023
Academy Certificate of Achievement, Uncommon Sports Group, Minneapolis, MN 2022
Dean's List, Marist College, Poughkeepsie, NY
National Society of Leadership and Success - 2021 - Present
Marist Analytics Community - 2021 - Present
Emerging Leaders Program - 2020 - 2021
The Triple C Award, Shaker High School, Latham, NY - Jun 2020
Given to a member of my high school's senior class who demonstrated the qualities of courage, character, and commitment.